

Solomon .E. Eseme

Senior Software Engineer

Lagos, Nigeria

+2348145655380

www.codelikemad.com.ng

about.me/solomoneseme

Summary

I'm Solomon Eseme, a proficient software engineer specializing in back-end development, I have more than 4 years professional experience in software development, freelancing and instructing, with my level of experience and expertise, I'll love to join your team to learn more and contribute my quota to the growth and development of your organization.

Work experience

Software/application Development Instructor

Feb. 2018 - Till Date

APTECH COMPUTER CENTER

Software/Application Development Instructor)

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Administering trainings and practicals to students.
- Training students on Java,. Net, Web Development and advanced software engineering, DevOps, Agile Methodology etc.
- Successfully trained students to Android, Web, Enterprise Application Developers.
- Successfully trained students to qualify for a B.sc Degree through Credit Transfer to

Senior Back-end Engineer (Remotely)

Nov 2017 - Jan 2019

IPLAYFOOTBALL LIMITED

Senior Back-end Engineer

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Working on the requirement analysis
- Leading other team members for developments
- Working on database design
- Working on deploying to many cloud based hosting services
- Working with PHP/Laravel, Node. js/Express. js etc
- Planning, Coding, Testing and Deployment of applications

Human Resources Intern

February 2017 - December 2017

Nigeria LNG Limited

DEPARTMENTS

HRT, HRE, IMT

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Managing all documents.
- Act as customer service personnel for the department.
- Managing and arranging of interview venues.
- Working on Job Description (JD) and Competency Profiles in SAP.
- Working with IMT in creating an E-Commerce website application.
- Working with and teaching Advance Office Suites to staffs.

• Transposing Job Description on Excess with custom template.

Senior Training Instructor

Feb 2014 - Oct 2014

ADMAS I.T PLACE

Senior Training Instructor

RESPONSIBILITIES

- 1. Administering training and practicals to students.
- 2. Training students on Microsoft Office suites, Graphics etc.
- 3. Successfully trained students to become office secretaries, good communicator, good graphic and web designers etc.
- 4. Successfully trained students for international exams such as Microsoft Office 365.

Certifications

Certified Web Developer

Udemy

I have been certified in working with PHP and Laravel proficiently.

Certified Android Developer

2017

Udemy

Certified Android and Web Developer

2017

Andela Learning Community

Certified JavaScript Developer

2017

Udemy

Certified Java Developer

2014

ASPOT MICROSYSTEMS

Diploma in Secretarial Administration

2012 - 2013

ADMAS I.T PLACE

Higher Diploma in Desktop Publishing

2012 - 2013

ADMAS I.T PLACE

Education

B.Sc, Computer Science

2019 - 2021

NATIONAL OPEN UNIVERSITY

ABIA STATE POLYTECHNIC

WAEC 2007 - 2013

IHENACHOR MEMORIAL SECONDARY SCHOOL

FSLC - 2006

COMMUNITY PRIMARY SCHOOL

Portfolio

Portfolio is available on request

Skills

Java

PHP

Laravel

Node/Express

Others

1. JAVA -> Swing/JavaFX, Spring MVC and Spring boot, Servlet and JSP, Scala, etc

- 2. WEB Dev -> HTML5/CSS3, Javascript/NodeJS, PHP 7.x, Python 3.x, etc
- 3. FRAMEWORKS -> Laravel, DJango, Spring, Scala, Express, VUEJS, etc.
- 4. TOOLS -> C/C++, Git/Github, SVN, Docker, ATOM, VSCode, Android Studio, Maven, Gradle, Composer, PIP, NPM, etc
- 5. DEVOPS -> Jenkins, Docker, Nagios, Puppet, Chef, TravisCl, Ansible, Git, etc
- 6. OTHERS -> Microsoft Office Suite, Graphic Tools, etc